sarthaks.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy - Sarthaks eConnect | Largest Online Education Community

**Who we are and What this is** **:** The Sarthaks eConnect is an exclusive set of Q&A sites dedicated to provide high-quality questions and answers upto class 10+2, with the modest goal of making the Internet a better place. It is owned and operated by Sarthaks Digitizing India.

We take the private nature of your personal information very seriously, and are committed to protecting it. To do that, we’ve set up procedures to ensure that your information is handled responsibly and in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. We’re grateful for your trust, and we’ll act that way.

This privacy policy describes what information we collect when you visit the network, how we use that information, and what choices we offer you to access, update, and control it. This version of the policy is effective as of June 01, 2016.

**Types of Information:** “Personal information” is any information that we could use to identify an individual. It does not include personal information that is encoded or anonymized, or publicly available information that has not been combined with non-public information.

**How we collect information:** We collect information two ways: Information we get from your use of the network, and information you provide to us directly.

Information we get from your use of the network is primarily non-personally- identifying information of the sort that web browsers, servers, and services like Google Analytics* typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the time of each visit. Other non-identifying information that we might have access to includes how you use the service (e.g., search queries), your approximate location, cookies, etc.

We collect this non-personally identifying information in order to better understand how visitors use the service and where possible, to improve their experience. For instance, we may monitor the most common content on the network to help identify spam. In some cases, we may publicly display information that is not personally identifying in the aggregate, (e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the network,) or may provide it to third parties.

When you use the network, we also collect potentially personally identifying information in the form of Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. But we don’t use that information to identify you, and we handle and disclose these addresses in the same way we handle other potentially personally identifying information as described below.

Information you provide to us directly: Certain visitors to the network choose to interact with it in ways that may require them to provide us with personally identifying information. The amount and type of information that is provided depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for sarthaks.com to provide a username and email address.

If you send us a request, such as emailing us for support, we reserve the right to publish it (absent any personally identifying information) in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or help other users.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use cookies to help us track visitors’ use of the network and their preferences. If you do not wish to have cookies placed on your computer, you should set your browser to refuse cookies, but should be aware that certain features of the network may not function properly without them.

We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided us with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at [care@sarthaks.com](mailto:care@sarthaks.com) If we become aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we’ll delete it.

**Change of This Policy:** Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may occasionally need to change this policy. If we do update it, we’ll notify you either by posting the new policy on the network or by emailing you the changes or a link to the modified document. (See the “Choice” section below for information about how we’ll notify you if we change our policy regarding sensitive information.) In any case, the way we use information you provide will be covered by the privacy policy that was in effect at the time it was collected.

**Here are some of the ways we may use personal information you provide us:** To allow you to register for our web sites, Sarthaks eConnect and other services, and to administer and process those registrations;

To communicate with you about our products, services and related issues.

To evaluate the quality of our products and services, and to enhance your experience on our web sites.

If you are a registered user of the network and have supplied your email address, we may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with the network. We generally use the network to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of communication to a minimum. If we do send you information that you did not expressly request, we will provide you with a way to request that you don’t get any similar notices (opt-out).

**Security**  – All records containing personal or financial information are considered to be our property and are afforded confidential treatment at all times. We work hard to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of personal or financial information. All such electronic information is stored on restricted database servers, and is generally kept until such time as you may ask us to edit or delete it, as described below. We only disclose such information to our employees, agents or affiliates that a) need to know that information in order to process it for us or to provide other services, and b) have agreed not to disclose it to others.

**Data Integrity**  – In addition to assuring you that we will protect your personal information, we also want to make sure that it is reliable, accurate, and up-to-date. In order to do that, we provide:

**Access**  – Upon request, we will provide you with reasonable access to the personal information we collect about you. You will have the opportunity to correct, update, modify or delete this information by sending an e-mail to [care@sarthaks.com](mailto:care@sarthaks.com).

**Enforcement**  – We will conduct internal audits of our compliance with this privacy policy, including an annual self-assessment. Our team take your privacy as seriously as we do, and we will take all reasonable measures against any employee found to be in violation of this policy.

If you have any concerns or complaints about how you think we’ve handled your personal information, please contact [care@sarthaks.com](mailto:care@sarthaks.com)

**Contact Us** : If you have any questions about this policy or our site in general, please contact us [admin@sarthaks.com](mailto:admin@sarthaks.com)

***** Google Analytics is a registered trademark of Google, Inc.
